A Finding Aid to the Fred Mitchell Papers, 1938-2007, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Fred Mitchell papers
1938-2007
Archives of American Art
Mitchell, Fred, 1923-
AAA.mitcfred
Archival Resource Key
14.3 Linear feet
The papers of Fred Mitchell, 1938-2007, measure 14.3 linear feet. Correspondence, writings, 29 diaries, and subject files, document his personal life and career as a painter and educator in New York City. The papers also include biographical materials, artwork, sketchbooks, printed material, and photographs.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Fred Mitchell donated a small amount of printed material and photographs in 1972. The majority of the papers were donated in 2013 by Fred Pajerski, Fred Mitchell's nephew.
Conditions Governing Access
Use of original material requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in 9 series:
Missing Title
Series 1: Biographical Materials,1942-circa 2005 (Box 1; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1947-2004 (Boxes 1-2; 1.9 linear feet)
Series 3: Writings, circa 1940s-2004 (Boxes 2-3; 1.4 linear feet)
Series 4: Diaries, 1949-2002 (Boxes 4-6; 2.5 linear feet)
Series 5: Subject Files, 1943-2002 (Boxes 6-12; 6 linear feet)
Series 6: Artwork, circa 1940s-2002 (Boxes 12-13; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 7: Sketchbooks, 1955-1993 (Boxes 13, 15; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 8: Printed Material, 1938-2004 (Boxes 13-14; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 9: Photographs, 1940s-2002 (Box 14; 0.5 linear feet)
Biographical / Historical
Fred Mitchell (1923-2013), a painter and educator who worked in New York City, was among the first artists to open a studio in Coenties Slip on the East River in downtown Manhattan.
A native of Meridian, Mississippi, Madison Fred Mitchell (always called Fred), won a Scholastic Magazine award and his work was shown in its "15th Annual National High School Art Exhibit" held at the museum of the Carnegie Institute in 1942. Mitchell studied at the Carnegie Institute of Technology for a year before entering the U. S. Army. After World War II ended, he resumed his education at Cranbrook Academy of Art (BFA 1946 and MFA 1956). He moved to New York in 1951 and became a member of the "Downtown Group." In 1952 he was among the organizers of Tanager Gallery and in 1954 founded the Coenties Slip School of Art.
Mitchell enjoyed a long career as a highly regarded teacher of drawing, painting, and art history. He taught at Finch College, the Positano Art Workshop in Italy, and Cranbrook Academy in the 1950s. During the 1960s, he was affiliated with Downtown Art Center at Seamens Church Institute in Coenties Slip, New York University, Cornell University, and Ithaca College. In the early 1970s Mitchell taught at Queens College, and from the mid-1980s-early 2000s served on the faculties of Parsons School of Design, Art Students League of New York, and City University of New York's Kingsborough Community College in Brooklyn.
He exhibited widely in group shows and solo exhibitions in the New York area and throughout the United States. Among these venues were: Howard Wise Gallery, Meridian Museum, Munson-Williams-Proctor Art Institute, State University of New York Binghamton, University of Oregon, and Whitney Museum of American Art.
After several years of declining health, Fred Mitchell died in New York City in 2013.
Scope and Contents
The papers of Fred Mitchell, 1938-2007, measure 14.3 liner feet. Correspondence, writings, 29 diaries, and subject files document his personal life and career as a painter and educator in New York City. The papers also include biographical materials, artwork, sketchbooks, printed material, and photographs.
Among the biographical materials are biographical notes, military records, passports, and resumes. Correspondence includes both professional and personal letters. Correspondents include friends, former students, colleagues, and individuals of romantic interest.
Writings by Mitchell include notebooks containing names and addresses, appointments, lists and a variety of notes. Diaries record Mitchell's personal and professional activities, plans, aspirations, and memories; also, many volumes contain loose items such as printed material, drawings, notes and letters. Other authors represented are Harry Hope Reed, Peter Rooney, and Patrick Rucker.
Subject files maintained by Mitchell concern friends, teaching activities, exhibitions; also, interests in art, dance, poetry, and music. Files on the Mitchell family concern four generations and include Elizabeth Pajerski, his artist sister with whom he sometimes exhibited. There are files on Coenties Slip artists and related exhibitions. Other subjects of note are a Franz Kline traveling exhibition curated by Mitchell, and Mississippi Art Colony. Individuals for whom threre are substantial subject files include Justo Gonzales, James M. McQuade, Jim Ochman, Peter Rooney, John W. ("Dicky") Stevens, and Phil Sultz.
Most artwork is by Mitchell and consists mainly of drawings and sketches. Artwork by others includes drawings and watercolors by Peter Rooney, students, and unidentified artists. Mitchell's sketchbooks (16 volumes) contain sketches, drawings, and a few finished watercolors.
Printed material is about or mentions Mitchell. Included are a variety of items such as exhibition catalogs and announcements, brochures, clippings, press releases, and concert programs. Photographs are of Mitchell with family and friends; artwork by Mitchell and other artists; exhibition installations and openings; and places including the Wall-South neighborhood just before the destruction of his studio and travel pictures.
Diaries; Photographs; Art -- Study and teaching; Sketches; Scrapbooks; Watercolors; Painters -- New York (State) -- New York; Drawings; Gonzales, Justo; Kline, Franz, 1910-1962; McQuade, James M.; Rucker, Patrick; Stevens, Dick, 1928-; Sultz, Phil; Mississippi Art Colony; Ochman, Jim; Pajerski, Elizabeth; Reed, Harry Hope; Rooney, Peter
- Biographical Materials, 1942-circa 2005; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents
  The folder titled "Awards and Certificates" contains a certificate of merit from Scholastic Magazine with a letter and copy of the issue containing an article about its "15th Annual National High School Art Exhibition" (1942) held at the Carnegie Institute. Also included is Mitchell's artist certification issued by New York City.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Address Books, undated; 1960-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Addresses and Phone Numbers, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Astrological Chart by Peter, circa 1990s-circa 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Awards and Certificates, 1982; 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Biographical Notes, circa 1990s-circa 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Diplomas, 1942; 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Legal Documents, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Military Records, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Passports, Drivers License, Voter Registration, 1956-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Resumes, circa 1960s-circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1947-2004; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 1.9 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Correspondence is professional and personal in nature, with incoming letters predominant. Correspondents include friends, former students, colleagues, and individuals of romantic interest. There are letters concerning exhibition and employment opportunities as well as routine personal business.
  Correspondence is arranged by year. A significant amount of additional correspondence is found in subject files. Some individual and institutional correspondents in this series may have subject files dedicated to them (Series 5), and loose letters are scattered throughout Mitchell's diaries (Series 4).
  - Correspondence, 1947-1960s; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12-17)
  - Correspondence, 1947-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, circa 1967-circa 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1970s-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1-20)
- Writings, circa 1940s-2004; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 1.4 Linear feet Boxes 3-4
  Mitchell's writings include an article, notes, student papers, and a videocassette of his participation in an Art Students League panel discussion. Twenty six pocket notebooks contain names and addresses, appointments, lists, and notes (some notes are akin to brief diary entries). Writings by others include poems and an article. Of particular interest is Peter Rooney's unpublished Fred Mitchell catalogue raisonne with notes.
  Writings by Mitchell are arranged by record type and filed alphabetically by folder title. Writings by others are alphabetized by author.
  - By Mitchell, Archival Resource Key (Box 3)
    - Article, "Design in America: The Cranbrook Vision 1925-1950" in American Craft, vol. 44, no. 2, 1984 April - 1984 May; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2-19)
    - Notes, undated; 1969-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20-34)
    - Notes, Renaissance to 19th Century Course, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Notes from Trips, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Notes, Sojourning, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Notebooks, 1963-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 38-41)
    - Panel Discussion, Art Students League Forum, Raw and Upfront, "How Artists Happen", 1997; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Student Papers, circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - By Others, Archival Resource Key (Box 4)
    - Louderson and Unidentified Authors. Poems, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Reed, Harry Hope. Brochure for NYC Bicycle Tour sponsored by Friends of the Parks, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Rooney, Peter. Fred Mitchell Catalogue Raisonné with Notes, 1994-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Rucker, Patrick. "Reflections on the Helican Festival at Weill Hall", 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Diaries, 1949-2002; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 2.5 Linear feet Boxes 4-6
  Diaries (29 volumes) record Mitchell's personal and professional activities, plans, aspirations, and memories. Entries range from extremely brief notes to lengthy, substantial reflections on the day's events. Most volumes contain drawings and sketches; many also include loose items such as clippings, letters, notes, drawings, and printed material. Sometimes coins are attached, accompanied by a personal memory relating to the coin's date. A substantial number of diary entries were recorded on loose sheets of paper.
  Volumes are numbered and arranged chronologically. Several volumes contain overlapping dates; some record multiple years, and some years fill more than a single volume. Entries on loose pages, also arranged by year, follow volume 29.
  - Volume 1, 1949-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Volume 2, 1957-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Volume 3, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Volume 4, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Volume 5, 1971-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Volume 6, 1977-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Volume 7, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Volume 8, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Volume 9, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Volume 10, 1985-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Volume 11, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Volume 12, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Volume 13, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Volume 14, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Volume 15, 1987-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Volume 16, 1987-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Volume 17, 1988-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Volume 18, 1988-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Volume 19, 1989-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Volume 20, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Volume 21, 1991-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Volume 22, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Volume 23, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Volume 24, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Volume 25, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Volume 26, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Volume 27, 1994-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Volume 28, 1996-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Volume 29, 1997-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Diary Entries on Loose Pages, undated; 1969-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4-19)
- Subject Files, 1943-2007; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 6 Linear feet Boxes 6-12
  Subject files contain varying combinations of correspondence, printed material, writings, art work and photographs that document Mitchell's family, friendships, exhibitions, teaching, and his interests in art, dance, poetry, and music. Individuals for whom there are substatial subject files include: Justo Gonzales, James M. McQuade, Jim Ochman, Peter Rooney, John W. ("Dicky") Stevens, and Phil Sultz.
  This series is alphabetized by file title.
  - 128 Front Street, New York City, circa 1952-circa 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Agostini, Peter, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1984-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Anatomy, Human, circa 1950s-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 23-24)
  - Anderson, Walter, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Animals and Birds, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - The Arkansas Arts Center, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Arnold, Bruce ("Brucerino"), 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - The Armillary Sphere, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Art and Artists of Mississippi, 1790-1980, the first volume in "The New Mississippi Heritage Series" to be published in 1998, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Art Awards, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - The Art Students League, undated; 1975-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 32-34)
  - Artz, Tony, "Woman of Change", undated; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (U-matic) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Ashbury, John, 1992, Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Aspen School of Contemporary Art and Aspen Art Gallery, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Auction Debacle, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Augusta, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Barcroft, George, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Barron, Alton, 1984-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Baton Rouge, Louisiana, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Becker, Boris, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Battcock, Gregory, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Beauchamp, Bob, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Benca, Adolf, 1980-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Bialski, David, 1983-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Birthdays and Anniversaries, undated; 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Bohary, Jim, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Brask, Ole, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Bronson, Duane, 1979-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Bronxville, "Drawings and Paintings: Southern Tipping, Coenties Slipping" (1999 September 17-1979 October 22), Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - "Brother-Sister Exhibit, Fred Mitchell and Elizabeth Pajerski," Marie Hull Gallery, Hinds Junior College, Raymond, Mississippi (1979), Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Buddhism, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Bueckner & Harpsichords, 1972-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Burton, Fred, "Freddie B the postcard king", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Cage, John, 1982-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Cape Cod -- Provincetown Art Association and Museum; Castle Hill, Truro Center for the Arts, undated; 1990-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - "Capturing Meridian", 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Coenties Slip, 1974-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Coenties Slip Artists, 1958-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Coenties Slip Exhibition, Buecher & Harpsichords (1973 January -- 1973 February), Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Coenties Slip Studio, 1955-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Columbia University, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Congregation Beth Elohim Art Exhibition and Sale, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Cornell University, 1968-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Cranbrook Academy of Art/ The Cranbrook Educational Community, 1965-1994; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Crellin, John ("Giovanni"), 1981-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Merce Cunningham Dance Company, 1970-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Dalai Lama, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Dali, Salvadore, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Dance, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Dawson, Bess, The Summit Studio, Gulf South Gallery, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - De Lallier, Alex, 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Delaware Art Museum, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Dickerman, Henry E., 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Doughty, Thomas, South Branch of the Potomac, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Downtown Art Center, circa 1960s-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Dunn, Douglas, 1979-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - The Eden Isle Art Colony, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Elrick, Marc and Glenn Lanteigne, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Enrico, 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Exhibitions, Lower East Side, 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Family, Archival Resource Key (Box 7)
    - Mitchell, James Milton (nephew), undated; 1960s-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Mitchell, Thomas Lyle (brother) and Marie Mitchell, undated; 1960s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1-4)
    - Mitchell, Thomas Lyle, Jr. (nephew), undated; 1960s-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Pajerski, Elizabeth Mitchell (sister) and Frank Pajerski, undated; 1950-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6-16)
    - Pajerski, Fred Mitchell (nephew), undated; 1960s-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 17-18)
  - Fellah, Serge, circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Figures, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - "Four Abstract Artists: Recent Works by John Loy, James McDermid, Fred Mitchell, Easton Pribble," The Central New York Arts Commission Gallery, Utica, NY (1992), 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - "Four Painters: Bohary, Engleson, Passlat, Rich" (1976 November), Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - "Four Viewpoints," Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute School of Art (1977 November 9 -- 1977 November 23), Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Friends' Exhibitions, Visual and Athletic, undated; 1980s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Fundació Antoni Tapies, 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Gallery X, 1998-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Garabedian, Robert, 1976-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - "The Gathering of the Avant-Garde: The Lower East Side, 1948-1970" (1985), Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Gonzales, Justo, 1983-1993; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 29-33)
  - Gonzalez, Justo, and Giving Out my Books, 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Adolph and Esther Gottlieb Foundation, Inc., 1989-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Grant Possibilities, 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Greater Lafayette Museum of Art, Lafayette, Indiana, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Greene, Johnny, 1968-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Greig, Dudley B., 1964-1991; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
  - Gros, Nancy, 1958-1961; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Gruder, Beth, 1966-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - The Solomon R. Guggenheim Musuem, "Younger American Painters" (1954-1955), 1954-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Guyton, Jeff, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Hale, Robert Beverly, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Hamilton, William ("Bimbo Tomasso"), 1970s-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Haring, Keith, 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Hartley, Marsden, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Heilman, Philip, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Heliker, Jack, 1970s-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Hoenig, Adele ("Adelina"), 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Hofmann, Hans, 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Hopson, Allan, 1975-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Hughes, Robert, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Hunterdon Art Center, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Ippolito, Angelo, 1968-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Italy, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Ithaca College, 1969-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Jessup, Andy, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Job Applications, 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Job Possibilities, 1960s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Johnson, Meryl, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Judson Memorial Church Centennial, 1986-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Kearchler, Tom, 1975-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Kelly, Ellsworth, 1981-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Kingsborough Community College, Archival Resource Key (Box 9)
    - Kingsborough Community College, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - New Course, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 33)